<chapter id="aimaccount">
	<title>Adding an AIM account</title>

	<para>
		To add an AIM account, click &quot;Add&quot; on the &quot;Accounts&quot;
		window.  The following appears:
		<figure>
			<title>Add Account Dialog</title>
			<graphic fileref="../images/addaccountdialog.png"/>
		</figure>
	</para>

	<para>
		Since we're adding an AIM account, the Protocol field is already set to
		what we want. Here's a quick breakdown of what all the fields you see
		mean:
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<tbody valign="center">
				<row>
					<entry>
						Username
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Enter the screen name you want to log in with here
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						Password
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Enter the password for the screen name here
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						Remember password
					</entry>
					<entry>
						If you don't want to have to type your password every
						time you launch Pidgin,	you can feel free to click this
						checkbox.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						Local alias
					</entry>
					<entry>
						This field allows you to specify a name for yourself
						that only you will see.  You may wish to set this field
						to something like &quot;Me&quot; or your name, initials,
						etc.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						New mail notifications
					</entry>
					<entry>
						If you use AIM Mail, or otherwise have a mail account
						tied to your screen name in such a way that the AIM
						servers can check for new mail, checking this box will
						display a notification when new mail arrives
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						Use this buddy icon for this account
					</entry>
					<entry>
						This checkbox, when enabled, allows you to use the icon
						selector below it to choose a buddy icon specific to
						this account or to use the &quot;Remove&quot; button to
						clear an account-specific buddy icon.  We'll discuss
						buddy icons later.
					</entry>
				</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</para>

	<para>
		Now that we've gone over the basics, let's see what a typical AIM account
		might look like:
		<figure>
			<title>A Configured AIM Account</title>
			<graphic fileref="../images/populatedaimaccount.png"/>
		</figure>
	</para>
</chapter>
