<chapter id="gettingstarted">
	<title>Getting Started</title>

	<para>
		Welcome to the Pidgin User's Guide!  It's our hope that this guide will
		address a number of concerns about Pidgin lacking user documentation.
	</para>

	<para>
		To get started, let's summarize some of Pidgin's features:

		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				Multiprotocol support:
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						AOL Instant Messenger (AIM)
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						Bonjour (formerly Rendezvous)
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						Extensible Messaging and Presence Protocol (XMPP,
						formerly Jabber)
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						Gadu-Gadu
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						Google Talk (this is XMPP with some additional extensions)
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						ICQ
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						Internet Relay Chat (IRC)
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						MyspaceIM
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						Novell Groupwise Messenger
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						QQ
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						Sametime
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						Secure Internet Live Conferencing (SILC)
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						SIP/SIMPLE (we call this SIMPLE)
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						Windows Live Messenger (formerly MSN; we call it MSN)
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						Yahoo! Messenger (we call this Yahoo)
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						Zephyr
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				Buddy icons (avatars)
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				Offline messaging on numerous protocols
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				Combining multiple buddies into a single Contact
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				Ability to use multiple IM accounts at the same time, even
				multiple accounts using the same protocol
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				Support for &quot;Current Media&quot; or &quot;User Tune&quot;
				on protocols supporting it
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				Multiple conversations in a single window using a tabbed interface
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				Multi-user Chats (MUCs) on all protocols which support them
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				A flexible plugin system allowing the addition or modification
				of features
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				Smiley themes which can change the appearance of default smileys
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				Status messages on all protocols which support them
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				File transfer on numerous protocols
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				Display of buddy icons (avatars) on buddy list window
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				Comprehensive and flexible status system
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				Ability to add multi-user chats to the buddy list for convenient
				access to frequently used chatrooms
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				Configurable sound notifications for numerous events
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</para>

	<para>
		Now let's take a look at running Pidgin for the first time.  We'll make
		the assumption that you already know how to find and launch Pidgin by
		using a shell or a graphical menu system such as Windows' Start menu or
		an X11 window manager's application menus.  When you first launch Pidgin,
		you'll see something similar to the figure below:
		<figure>
			<title>Pidgin First Launch Window</title>
			<graphic fileref="../images/firstlaunchwindow.png"/>
		</figure>
	</para>

	<para>
		As the window says, you need to configure accounts.  We'll cover that in
		several chapters covering creating an account for each protocol.
	</para>
</chapter>
