<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<sect1 id="aimaccount">
	<title>Adding an AIM account</title>

	<para><emphasis role="bold">About AIM</emphasis></para>

	<para>
		AIM, the AOL Instant Messenger, is one of the older public IM networks,
		and in our experience one of the most reliable.  It's the first protocol
		Pidgin ever supported.  AOL users can talk on the AIM network, but
		AIM-only users far outnumber them.  AIM also supports interoperability
		with ICQ, including messaging and adding ICQ users to the AIM buddy
		list.
	</para>

	<para>
		AIM uses the OSCAR protocol, which has recently been opened to those IM
		client developers who agree to the terms of use surrounding the API and
		documentation made available.  ICQ shares the OSCAR protocol with AIM,
		as well as overlapping servers, which is the basis of the cross-service
		interoperability just mentioned.  We show two protocol entries, one for
		AIM and one for ICQ, as a matter of convenience, as few people would
		understand what OSCAR meant if we listed that instead. :)
	</para>

	<para><emphasis role="bold">Adding an AIM account</emphasis></para>

	<para>
		To add an AIM account, click &quot;Add&quot; on the &quot;Accounts&quot;
		window.  The following appears:
		<figure>
			<title>Add Account Dialog</title>
			<graphic fileref="../src/images/addaimaccount.png"/>
		</figure>
	</para>

	<para>
		Since we're adding an AIM account, the Protocol field is already set to
		what we want. Here's a quick breakdown of what all the fields you see
		mean:
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<tbody valign="center">
				<row>
					<entry>
						Username
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Enter the screen name you want to log in with here
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						Password
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Enter the password for the screen name here
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						Remember password
					</entry>
					<entry>
						If you don't want to have to type your password every
						time you launch Pidgin,	you can feel free to click this
						checkbox.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						Local alias
					</entry>
					<entry>
						This field allows you to specify a name for yourself
						that only you will see.  You may wish to set this field
						to something like &quot;Me&quot; or your name, initials,
						etc.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						New mail notifications
					</entry>
					<entry>
						If you use AIM Mail, or otherwise have a mail account
						tied to your screen name in such a way that the AIM
						servers can check for new mail, checking this box will
						display a notification when new mail arrives
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						Use this buddy icon for this account
					</entry>
					<entry>
						This checkbox, when enabled, allows you to use the icon
						selector below it to choose a buddy icon specific to
						this account or to use the &quot;Remove&quot; button to
						clear an account-specific buddy icon.  We'll discuss
						buddy icons later.
					</entry>
				</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</para>

	<para>
		You probably noticed that there is an &quot;Advanced&quot; tab on this
		window.  You can safely ignore this for now.  We'll come back to it and
		explain more later.
	</para>

	<para>
		Now that we've gone over the basics, let's see what a typical AIM account
		might look like:
		<figure>
			<title>A Configured AIM Account</title>
			<graphic fileref="../src/images/populatedaimaccount.png"/>
		</figure>
	</para>
</sect1>
